Register of the Jay Lovestone papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1906-1978 (Boxes 396-589)
  - Alliance for Progress (Box 401)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
  - American Association for Economic Freedom
  - American Association for the United Nations
  - American China Policy Association
  - American Civil Liberties Union
  - American Committee for a Free Spanish Republic
  - American Committee for Freedom for the Peoples of the U.S.S.R.
  - American Committee for Liberation
  - American Committee on Africa
  - American Committee on United Europe
  - American Council of Young Political Leaders
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL)
    - General
      - Constitution
      - Conventions, conferences
      - Correspondence
      - Financial documents (Box 402)
      - Meeting notes
      - Miscellaneous
      - Office memoranda
      - Pamphlets, leaflets, flyers
      - Reports (Box 403)
      - Resolutions
      - Speeches
      - Statements
    - European Bureau
    - Executive Council
    - Free Trade Union Committee
    - International Executive Board (Box 404)
    - International Labor Relations Committee
    - International relations
    - Postwar Committee
    - Training School in International Affairs
    - Woll, Matthew
  - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)
    - General
      - General
      - Constitution
      - Conventions, conferences (Box 405)
      - Correspondence (Box 406)
      - Correspondence (Box 407)
      - Financial documents (Box 408)
        - 1963
        - 1964 (Box 409)
        - 1965
        - 1966 (Box 410)
        - 1968
      - Meeting notes
      - Miscellaneous
      - Office memoranda
      - Office memoranda (Box 411)
      - Office memoranda (Box 412)
      - Printed material (Box 413)
      - Reports
      - Resolutions
      - Speeches
      - Statements (Box 414)
    - Committee on Political Education (Box 415)
    - Department of International Affairs
    - Executive Council
    - Free Trade Union Committee
      - General
      - Correspondence
      - Financial documents, 1954-1958 (Box 416)
    - Free Trade Union News (Box 417)
    - Industrial Union Department
    - Inter-American Affairs Committee
    - International Affairs Department
    - International relations
    - Labor Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance
    - Labor Studies Center
    - Maritime Trades Department
    - Meany, George
      See separate listing under Meany.
    - Merger
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (Box 418)
  - American Federation of Teachers
  - American Friends of the Captive Nations
  - American Independent Party
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD) (Box 419)
  - American Jewish Committee
  - American Labor Conference
  - American Labor Party (Box 420)
  - American leaders
  - American League
  - American League Against War and Fascism
  - American Negro Labor Congress, 1925 October
  - American Security Council
  - American Society of African Culture
  - American Veterans Group
  - American Writers Association
  - Americans for Democratic Action
  - Americans for Traditional Liberties
  - Americans for Winning the Peace
  - Americans of Italian Origin for Good Government
  - Americans United for World Organization
  - Amnesty International
  - Amter, Israel (Box 421)
  - Angola
  - Annalist (typed excerpt), 1925 June 29
  - Anti-Americanism
  - Anti-communism
  - Anti-Semitism
  - Anti-war
  - Antioch College
  - Argentina
  - Armed Forces Information School
  - Armenia
  - Arms control
  - Asia
  - Asian-American Free Labor Institute (Box 422)
  - Asian Socialist Conference
  - Aspinook Corporation
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations
  - Associated Student Governments
  - Association of Hungarian Students in North America
  - Atlantic Charter
  - Atlantic Council
  - Atlantic Council (Box 423)
  - Atlantic Institute (Box 424)
  - Atlantic Institute of International Affairs
  - Atlantic Treaty Association
  - Atomic bomb
  - Atomic energy
  - Auslandskomitee der I.H.V. (Internationalehilfe Vereinigung)
  - Australia
  - Austria
    - General
    - Plebiscite leaflets, 1938
  - Automation (Box 425)
  - Automative Daily News (typed excerpts), 1937
  - Avco
  - Bahamas
  - Bahrein
  - Bail, Alexander (Miles, George F.)
  - Balance of payments
  - Balkan Peninsula
  - Baltic States
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company vs. Dora Goodman
  - Banerji, Jogindra
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl
  - Banks and banking
  - Baran, Paul
  - Barron's (typed excerpts), 1924-1925
  - Barth, Karl
  - Barton, Paul
  - Beard, Charles A.
  - Beck, David
  - Bedacht, Max (Barber)
  - Belgium
  - Benton, William, "The Soviet Economic Challenge"
  - Bergeron, Andre
  - Berlin
  - Bernard, Frantisek (Box 426)
  - Betancourt, Juan R.
  - Bevan, Aneurin
  - Bevin, Ernest
  - Bialer, Seweryn
  - Biddle, Francis
  - Biemiller, Andrew
  - Billik, Cyril D.
    - Correspondence, 1919-1920
    - Diary
      - 1906
      - 1919
        - Paris Peace Conference, March 19-April 16
        - April 17-May 23
        - November-December
      - 1920 February, June
    - Memoranda
  - Blum, Leon
  - Bolivia
  - Bolloten, Burnett
  - Borisoff B., "The Need of the Hour - Organization of Hands Off China Committees,", circa 1927
  - Borochowicz, Elly (Box 427)
  - Bourguina, Anna
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Brandler, Heinrich
  - Brandt, Willy
  - Bridges, Harry (Box 428)
  - British Guiana
  - British-North American Committee
  - British Press Service
  - Brockway, Fenner
  - Brophy, John
  - Brotherhood of Firemen and Engineers
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers
  - Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen
  - Browder, Earl
  - Brown, Irving
  - Brown, William Montgomery, Bishop
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew
  - Bukharin, Nikolai (Box 429)
  - Bulgaria
  - Bundy, William P.
  - Burke, Arleigh P.
  - Burma
  - Burman, Fahle
  - Business
  - Business cycles
  - Buu, Tran Quoc
  - Byrnes, James F.
  - Cameroon
  - Cambodia
  - Canada
  - Cannon, James P. (Box 430)
  - Canter, H. J.
  - Capitalism
  - Capovilla, Lors
  - Carey, James
  - Carter, Jimmy
  - Catholic Church
  - Center for Community Change
  - Center for Strategic Studies
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors
  - Centre Antiimperialiste
  - Centre Marxiste Revolutionaire International
  - Ceylon
  - Challenge
  - Chamberlain, William Henry
  - Chapman, Abraham
  - Chemical industry
  - Child labor
  - Children
  - Chile (Box 431)
  - China
    - General
    - Agriculture
    - Airlines
    - Atomic energy
    - Communism
    - Democratic Revolutionary League of Communist Party
    - Economic conditions
    - Education
    - Eighth Route Army (Box 432)
    - Emigration
    - Forced labor
    - Foreign relations
      - General
      - Algeria
      - India
      - Japan
      - Russia
      - Tibet
      - United States
    - History
      - General
      - 1949-
    - Hsi-shuang-pan-na
    - International economic relations
    - Labor
    - Mao Tse-tung
    - Maps
    - Miscellaneous
    - National income
    - Philosophy (Box 433)
    - Political exiles
    - Politics and government
    - Printed material
    - Religion
    - Sinkiang
    - Social conditions
    - Trade
    - Trade unions
    - Tsinghai (Box 434)
    - United Nations
    - Visitors
    - Welfare fund
  - Chinese American Society for Democracy in China
  - Chinese Federation of Labor
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Chrysler, Walter P.
  - Churchill, Winston
  - Citizen Exchange Corps
  - Citrine, Walter
  - Civil rights
  - Clark, Mark
  - Clay, Lucius D.
  - Cleaver, Eldridge
  - Cleveland, Harlan
  - Cloak Makers Union
  - Coal mining
  - Coalition for a Democratic Majority
  - Coffee industry
  - Coffin, Frank M., Aid and a Striving World (galleys)
  - Cohen, Benjamin
  - Cohen, Ross
  - Coletti, Henry T.
  - Collective bargaining
  - Colombia
  - Colonialism
  - Colson, Charles (Box 435)
  - Columbia University
  - Columbus Day Speech
  - Commercial and Financial Chronicle
  - Commission Internationale contre le Regime Concentrationnaire
  - Commission Internationale pour l'Aide aux Refugies Espagnols
  - Commission on Productivity
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace
  - Committee for a National Trade Policy
  - Committee for Abolition of Enslavement
  - Committee for Economic Development
  - Committee for Progressive American Unionism
  - Committee for Socialist Unity
  - Committee of Correspondence
  - Committee of One Million
  - Committee on Fair Play in Sports
  - Committee on Free Elections in the Dominican Republic
  - Committee on Industrial Committees
  - Committee to Combat Soviet Kidnappings
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies
    - General
      - General (Box 436)
      - Financial documents
    - Citizens for Victory - Press Service (Box 437)
    - Citizens for Victory - Press Service (Box 438)
    - Labor and Defense - Press Service
  - Committee to Unite America
  - Committees of Correspondence - Council for Community Action
  - Common Cause
  - Common Committee of East Exiles in Denmark
  - Common Council for American Unity
  - Common Market
  - Communism
    - General (Box 439)
    - Europe (Box 440)
    - France
    - United States
  - Communist
  - Communist International
  - Communist Party
    - Cuba
    - United States
  - Communist trade unions (Box 441)
  - Communists - U.S.
  - Confederazione Sindacale Italiana dei Lavoratori
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action
  - Conference for Progressive Political Action
  - Conference on Transatlantic Technological Collaboration
  - Congo
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
  - Congress of Peoples Against Imperialism
  - Connecticut - Economic conditions
  - Conscription
  - Constituent Assembly
  - Cooke, Alistair
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Cooperation Internationale pour le Developpement Socio-Economique
  - Cooperative Central Exchange (Box 442)
  - Coordinating Center for Democratic Opinion
  - Corbin, Paul
  - Cornell University - International Labor Training Program
  - Corning Conference, 1961
  - Corporation Counsel, New York, circa 1937
  - Costa Rica
  - Coste, Brutus
  - Costick, Miles M., "Economics of Detente and U.S. - Soviet Grain Trade"
  - Council Against Communist Aggression
  - Council for American-Italian Affairs
  - Council on Foreign Relations
  - Coyle, Albert F. (Box 443)
  - Crusade for a Free Democratic China
  - Cryptography
  - Cuba
  - Cuneo, Ernest (Box 444)
  - Cyprus
  - Cyprus Workers Confederation
  - Czechoslovakia
    - General (Box 445)
    - Anti-communist movements
    - Benes, Edvard
    - Capek, Karel
    - Economic conditions
    - Education
    - Forced labor
    - History
      - 1918-1938
      - 1938-1945
      - 1945
      - Intervention, 1968
      - Intervention, 1968 (Box 446)
    - Masaryk, Thomas
    - Miscellaneous
    - Politics and government
    - Slansky, Rudolf
    - Svitak, Ivan
    - Trade unions
    - Trade unions (Box 447)
    - Underground movements
  - Daily European Observations (Box 448)
  - Daily Worker
  - Dallin, David
  - Dan, Phan Quang
  - Das, S. R. Mohan
  - Davies, John
  - Davis, John W.
  - Dawes, Charles G.
  - Dawes Plan
  - Dean, Arthur H.
  - Debs, Eugene
  - Declaration of Atlantic Unity
  - Defense bonds - Purchased by labor unions, 1941
  - Dematrocopulos, Elias
  - Democratic Party
  - Democratic Party and communism
  - Democracy
  - Denmark
  - Depressions, 1929
  - Deverall, Richard
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - Dillon, Douglas C.
  - Dimitrov, George
  - Disarmament
  - Diseases
  - Ditchley Foundation
  - Djilas, Milovan
  - Dodd, Thomas
  - Dodd, William E.
  - Dohrn, Klaus
  - Dominican Republic (Box 449)
  - Donovan, William J.
  - Douglas, William A.
  - Dozenberg, Nicholas
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Dubinsky, David
  - Dulles, Allen
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Dunn, Robert W.
  - Eastman, Max
  - Economic conditions
  - Eddy, Sherwood, "Russia, the Land of Contradictions"
  - Education
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
  - Egypt
  - Einstein, Albert
  - Elections
    - New York State, 1930
    - U.S., 1924
  - Emmet, Christopher (Box 450)
  - Employment
  - Employment opportunities
  - Empros
  - Engels, Friedrich
  - Epstein, Henry
  - Erhard, Ludwig
  - Espionage
  - Ethiopia
  - Europe
  - Europe (Box 451)
  - Europe, Eastern
  - European Recovery Program
  - European Trade Union Confederation
  - European War, 1914-1918
  - European War - Reparations, 1914-1918
  - Exchange programs, international
  - Export-Import Bank (Box 452)
  - Fabian Anglo-French Cooperation Committee
  - Farley, James
  - Farm workers
  - Farmer Labor Political Federation
  - Farmer's National Committee for Action
  - Farmer's Second National Conference
  - Farrell, James T.
  - Feather, Victor
  - Federal Trade Commission
  - Federated Farmer-Labor Press Service
  - Federation Nationale Force Ouvriere
  - Federation News
  - Ferri-Pisani, Pierre
  - Field, Marshall
  - Field, Noel
  - Finance
  - Finland
  - Flannery, Harry W., "March to Freedom" (Box 453)
  - Flood control
  - Food
  - Food relief
  - Food supply
  - Forced labor
  - Ford, Gerald R.
  - Foreign Exchange Control Board
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Foreign trade
  - Fortune, "Corporate Strategy in the Seventies"
  - Foster, William Z.
  - France
    - General
    - Agriculture (Box 454)
    - Communism
    - Communist Party
    - Couve de Murville, Maurice
    - Economic conditions
    - Foreign relations
      - General
      - Algeria
      - Tunisia
    - Gaulle, Charles de
    - History
      - 1914-1940
      - 1940-1945
      - 1945-
    - Maps
    - Politics and government
    - Refugees (Box 455)
    - Trade unions
  - Franco, Francisco
  - Free China Labor League (Box 456)
  - Free Trade Union Movement
  - Free World Labour Confederation
  - Freedom House
  - Freidin, Seymour, "American Labor Abroad"
  - Freiheit (typed excerpts)
  - Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung
  - Friends of Free China Association
  - Friends of Soviet Russia
  - Front Ouvrier International Contre La Guerre
  - Fulbright, William
  - Fulbright, William (Box 457)
  - Fund for New Priorities
  - Fund for Public Information
  - Fur industry
  - Furriers Joint Council
  - Furriers Trade Union League
  - Gabon
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
  - Gambia
  - Gandhi, Mohandas
  - General Motors
  - Genoa, Economic and Financial Conference, 1922
  - Genocide
  - Germany
    - General (Box 458)
    - Adenaur, Konrad
    - Anti-Semitism
    - Brandt, Willy
    - Communist Party
    - Economic conditions
      - 1918-1945
      - 1945-
    - Erhard, Ludwig
    - Espionage
    - Exchange program
    - Foreign relations
    - History
      - 1918-1933
        Includes typescript by August Thalheimer on situation in Germany, August 13, 1932.
      - 1933-1945
      - Allied occupation, 1945-
      - 1945-
    - Inside Germany Reports
    - Labor conscription (Box 459)
    - Leber, Georg
    - Miscellaneous
    - National Socialist German Labor Party (Nazis)
    - Ollenhauer
    - Politics and government
    - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD) (Box 460)
    - Sozialistische Arbeiter Partei
    - Trade unions
    - Underground literature (Box 461)
  - Germany, Democratic Republic, 1949-
  - Ghana
  - Gibraltar (Box 462)
  - Gitlow, Benjamin - Notes on book by Gitlow entitled I Confess
  - Glasser, Harold - Testimony before the House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1948 July 31
  - Globke, Hans
  - Goldberg, Arthur
  - Goldberg, Harry
  - Gompers, Samuel
  - Goodwin, William J.
  - Gorkin, Julian
  - Grain Trade
  - Granger, Lester B.
  - Great Britain
    - General
    - Economic conditions
    - Foreign relations
    - History
    - Maps
    - Politics and government
    - Printed material
    - Trade unions
  - Greece (Box 463)
  - Green, William
  - Griffith, Sanford
  - Gruenther, Alfred
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York
  - Guatemala
  - Guinea
  - Gumpertz, Julian
  - Guyana
  - Hadgis, Alex
  - Haig, Alexander
  - Haiti
  - Hammer, Armand
  - Harding, Warren G.
  - Harriman, Averell
  - Harrington, Michael
  - Harrison, George
  - Hawaii
  - Health
  - Helsinki Accord
  - Henson, Francis
  - Herberg, Will
  - John Herling's Labor Letter and newspaper columns (Box 464)
  - Herter, Christian
  - Hillman, Sidney
  - Hirlef Knitting Mill
  - Ho Chi Minh
  - Hobson, J. A.
  - Hoffa, James
  - Holy Land Center
  - Hong Kong
  - Hook, Sidney
  - Hoover, Herbert C.
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
  - Hoover Commission Report - Reorganization News
  - Housing
  - Hughes, Howard
  - Human rights
  - Humanité, L' (typed excerpt)
  - Humphrey, Hubert
  - Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation (Box 465)
  - Hungarian Labor in Exile
  - Hungarian National Council
  - Hungary
    - General
    - Agriculture
    - Economic conditions
    - History - Revolution, 1956
    - Jews
    - Kethly, Anna
    - Political prisoners (Box 466)
    - Politics and government
    - Printed material
    - Trade unions
    - United Nations
  - Iceland
  - Immigration
  - Imperialism
  - Independent Labour Party
  - Independent News
  - India
    - General
    - General (Box 467)
    - Communist Party
    - Congress Party
    - Das, S. R. Mohan - Reports and articles
    - Economic conditions
    - Fernandes, George
    - Foreign relations
      - General
      - China
      - Hungary
      - Pakistan
      - Russia
      - United States
    - Gandhi, Indira (Box 468)
    - History - 20th century
    - Industry
    - Joshi, N. M.
    - Kerala
    - Masses, The (photocopy and typed excerpt)
    - Menon, V. K. Krishna
    - National Commission on Labour
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal
    - Orissa
    - Politics and government
      - 1919-1947
      - 1947-
    - Roy, M. N.
    - Trade unions
    - United Nations
  - Indo-China (Box 469)
  - Indonesia
    - General
    - Armed forces
    - Economic conditions
    - Foreign relations
    - Maps
    - Politics and government
    - Religion
    - Trade unions
  - Industrial accidents (Box 470)
  - Industrial Conference, San Francisco, 1973
  - Industrial News
  - Industrial relations
  - Industrial research
  - Industry
  - Inflation (Finance)
  - Insider's Newsletter
  - Institute for American Strategy
  - Institute for International Solidarity
  - Institute for Policy Studies
  - Institute of International Labor Research
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
  - Instituto Americano Para el Desarrollo del Sindicalismo Libre
  - Intelligence service
  - Internal migration - Negro
  - International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada
  - International Association of Machinists
  - International Bill of Rights
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters
  - International Bureau for Revolutionary Socialist Unity
  - International business enterprises
  - International Center for Free Trade Unionists in Exile
  - International Chemical Workers Federation
  - International Commission of Jurists
  - International Communist Opposition
  - International Confederation of Christian Trade Unions
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box 471)
      - Correspondence (Box 472)
      - Meeting notes
      - Office memoranda
      - Press releases
      - Reports (Box 473)
      - Resolutions (Box 474)
      - Speeches
      - Statements
    - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)
    - Committee on Relations with Communist-Controlled Trade Union Organisations
    - Conference on Czechoslovakia
    - Congresses and conventions
      - First Congress, London, 1949
      - Second Congress, Milan, 1951 (Box 475)
      - Third Congress, Stockholm, 1953
      - Fourth Congress, Vienna, 1955 (Box 476)
      - Fifth Congress, Tunis, 1957
      - Sixth Congress, Brussels, 1959 (Box 477)
      - Seventh Congress, Berlin, 1962
      - Eighth Congress, Amsterdam, 1965 (Box 478)
      - Ninth Congress, Brussels, 1969 (Box 479)
      - Tenth Congress, London, 1972
    - Constitution
    - East-West Committee
    - Executive Board
      - Undated
      - 1950
      - 1951
      - 1952
      - 1953
      - 1954
      - 1955
      - 1956 (Box 480)
      - 1957
      - 1958
      - 1959
      - 1960
      - 1961
      - 1962 (Box 481)
      - 1963
      - 1964
      - 1965
      - 1966
      - 1967
      - 1968
      - 1969 (Box 482)
      - 1970
      - 1971
      - 1973
    - Information Bulletin
    - International Solidarity Fund Committee
    - Miscellaneous
    - Regional Fund Committee
    - Regional Offices (Box 483)
      - Africa
      - Asia
      - Europe
    - Seminar, Africa, 1955
    - Sub-committees
    - United Nations
  - International Development Institute
  - International Documentation and Information Center
  - International economic assistance
  - International economic conditions (Box 484)
  - International economic relations
  - International Federation of Building and Woodworkers
  - International Federation of Christian Trade Unions
  - International Federation of Industrial Organisations and General Workers Unions
  - International Federation of Petroleum Workers
  - International Federation of Trade Unions
  - International finance
  - International Industrial Conference
  - International labor activities
  - International Labor Defense (Box 485)
  - International Labor Organization
  - International Labor Press Association (ILPA) (Box 486)
  - International labor relations
  - International Labour Conference
  - International Labour Film Institute
  - International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU)
    - General
      - Campaign literature
      - Correspondence
      - Court cases (Box 487)
      - Meeting notes
      - Office memoranda
      - Press releases
      - Reports
      - Resolutions
      - Speeches
    - Congresses and conventions
    - Education Department
    - Wage Survey
  - International Longshoremen's Association (Box 488)
  - International Metal Trades Federation
  - International Metalworkers Federation
  - International Monetary Fund
  - International relations
  - International relations (Box 489)
  - International Relief Association for Victims of Fascism
  - International Solidarity Day (Box 490)
  - International Solidarity Fund
  - International Studies Institute
  - International Study Committee
  - International trade
  - International Trade Secretariat
  - International Transport Workers Federation
  - International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers
  - International Union of Food and Allied Workers Association
  - International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers
  - International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America
  - International Worker's Aid
  - International Workers Front Against War
  - International Working-Men's Association (I.W.M.A.)
  - "The Internationale" Minute Book, 1866-1869
  - Internationale Revolutionare Marxistische Zentrum, Das
  - Internationaler Gewerkschaftsbund (Box 491)
  - Internationale Vereinigung der Kommunistischen Opposition (I.V.K.O.)
  - Inventions
  - Iran
  - Iraq
  - Ireland
    - General
    - Humor
  - Irish Congress of Trade Unions
  - Islam
  - Israel
    - General
    - Dayan, Moshe (Box 492)
    - Eban, Abba
    - Embassy (United States) - Policy background reports, undated
    - Foreign relations
    - Tekoah, Yosef
    - Trade unions
    - Water Project
  - Italian-American Labor Council (Box 493)
  - Italy
    - General
    - Foreign relations
    - Politics and government
    - Printed material (Box 494)
    - Printed material (Box 495)
    - Trade unions (Box 496)
    - Trade unions (Box 497)